Joonas Suuronen

Engineer, Programmer, Game Developer

I am 24-year-old fresh Information and Communication technology graduate (IT engineer). I always have had a huge passion for technology and science. Especially computers and programming have always fascinated me. I watch science, technology and programming related videos and streams daily. Also, I always have some sort of programming projects active (usually related to video games) that I love to work on. Most people know me as an honest, active and social individual. I tend to do everything immediately and never let tasks pile up.



isuuronen9@gmail.com

+358 400368833



📍 Espoo, Suomi



www.banaanigames.com/

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Developer Metropolia, SAM-project

01/2022 - Present

Began by making thesis on this subject, but I was hired to continue further. To simplify, the project is about creating an application for simulation of surveillance of autonomus vehicles.

Details

- UI / UX Development.
- Team management.
- Other various tasks.

Contact: Pekko Lindblom, project manager pekko.lindblom@metropolia.fi, +358 504733152

Game Developer

Tutanet Ov

05/2020 - Present

Small group of developers have worked on game called "News Reacts" for years. I was hired to develop the UI and some core mechanics. The game shipped to Steam in 5/2022.

Details

- UI / UX.
- Core Mechanics.
- Optimization.

Contact: Jukka Soinila, CEO jukka.soinila@gmail.com, +358 415015856

Security Guard

Avarn Security

05/2017 - Present

Details

- Security services in many forms.
- Starting from 2022, mostly includes driving Nokia 5G vans.

EDUCATION

Information and Communication Technology Metropolia Unviversity of Applied Sciences

08/2018 - 11/2022

Security guard's degree

Edupoli and Amiedu

02/2018 - 02/2018

Matriculation examination

Leppävaara Upper Secondary School

08/2014 - 06/2017

SKILLS

Communication

Game Engines

Image & Audio handling

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Company: Banaani Games (01/2023 - Present)

- Also made website from scratch: www.banaanigames.com
- Mostly for selling my own game projects
- Can also sell various software services through the company

Various game projects (02/2019 - Present)

- Numerous game projects, mostly developed with Unity and C#.
- More serious project started late 2021 (WIP).
- Improved my full-stack skills by a huge margin.

ML / Al Game Director (2021)

- Machine learning artificial intelligence to direct events in a game.
- Made for client called Bigger Scope.
- Clusterizes playstyles and adapts to be more fun for each player.

Chess AI (2019)

- Basic console chess with C++.
- Minimax algorithm with Alpha-Beta pruning, easily wins humans.
- Player vs player, computer vs player, computer vs computer.

LANGUAGES

Finnish

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

German

Full Professional Proficiency

Swedish

Limited Working Proficiency

Limited Working Proficiency

INTERESTS

Technology

Programming

Video Games

Science

Gvm

Mathematics

Physics